# SYAHMI MOKHTAR

**EMAIL** 

**C** CONTACT

**LINKEDIN** 

syahmiez96@gmail.com

011-61680995

www.linkedin.com/in/syahmimokhtar

## **ABOUT ME**

I am an experienced web developer with a focus on front-end technologies, now transitioning into technical writing and other fields outside of development. Over the past three years, I contributed to various projects, where I developed dynamic applications and self-taught new web technologies to enhance my technical knowledge and create effective technical documentation.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### FREELANCE WORK

January 2023 - Present

Took time off to care for a family member and focus on personal growth. During this period, I engaged in various activities to enhance my skills and knowledge:

- Produced promotional videos of food menus and posted it via social platforms for engagements.
- Assisting in PC building projects, offering tailored advice to clients based on their requirements.
- Focused on building professional porfolio in IT field.
- Completed online courses in technical writing, web development, and software testing.
- Supported my sister in growing her affiliate marketing efforts on TikTok and Shopee.
- Assisting my father with house decorations, transforming property into a functional and welcoming homestay.
- Achieved an English proficiency certificate from EFSET.org, demonstrating advanced language skills.
- Planning to design user-friendly interfaces for a web and mobile car rental application, contributing to its UI/UX development.

#### MIMOS BERHAD

October 2019 - January 2023 WEB DEVELOPER (MIMOS BERHAD)

- Revamped website pages for a MIMOS technology, 'Mi-Mash' with a responsive and user-friendly UI.
- Contributed to the development of three software systems for government agencies (KEMAS and JAIS) as part of the Government Online Service Gateway (GOSG) project.
- Authored comprehensive user guides and manuals tailored for non-technical users.
- Developed an online school application system for kindergarten student (age 6) under KEMAS.
- Developed an online school application system for primary (Standard 1) under JAIS.
- Developed an online school application system for kindergarten student (age 6) under JAIS.
- Collaborated with business analysts to create effective and user-centric system wireframes using Axure RP.
- Designed, developed, and tested a full-fledged human resource (HR) system to enhance work optimization in a government agency.
- Performed unit testing on enhancements to ensure code quality before release.

## ASTRO MALAYSIA HOLDINGS - ASTRO GOSHOP

February 2019 - July 2019

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER INTERN

- Learnt and exposed to the concepts of e-commerce in Astro Go Shop.
- Built a new feature for bulk upload orders by uploading excel files into the web system.
- Designed and developed brief documentation on business flows for cashback points, item returns/exchange and gift cards.
- Developed filter tags for product categories for Astro Go Shop Website.
- Performed unit testing on enhancements made before code release.

#### **SKILLS**

- Skilled in producing deliverable documentation aligned with IEEE standards.
- Created user manuals in both Bahasa Malaysia and English for diverse audiences.
- Acquired knowledge in software testing techniques such as Black Box Testing, Boundary Value Analysis (BVA), and Postman for API testing.
- Self-taught in modern web development technologies including React, Next.js, Tailwind CSS, Material-UI, and React Bootstrap.
- Proficient in website wireframing using Axure RP, Justinmind, and Wix.
- Experienced in core web development technologies: HTML, CSS, PHP, MySQL, and PostgreSQL.
- Experienced with Organization Chart JavaScript component BALKAN APP (licensed version).
- Worked with licensed JavaScript libraries, including Balkan App (Organization Chart component) and AmCharts (data visualization).
- Familiar with design and editing tools such as Adobe Illustrator and Adobe Premiere Pro.
- Proficient in Microsoft Office tools, including Word, Excel, and Visio, for documentation and diagramming.

## **EDUCATION QUALIFICATIONS**

- Bachelor of Software Engineering Universiti Putra Malaysia (UPM) -CGPA -3.717
- Foundation in Agricultural Sciebce Asasi Sains Pertanian UPM (ASPER) -CGPA- 3.264

### **LANGUAGE PROFICIENCY**

- Malay: Speak and write excellently
- English: Speak and write understandably
- Arabic : Speak basic Arabic

## **ACHIEVEMENT & AWARDS**

- •Published a research paper in International Journal of Engineering and Advanced Technology (IJEAT) ISSN: 2249-8958 (Online), Volume-9 Issue-1, October, 2019
- Obtained a EF SET English Certificate (C1 Advanced) Issued August 2024
- Finalists for Innovate Malaysia Design Competion (IMDC 2018) under google track for central region.
- Winner of FYP Poster Presentation 2018 (3rd place).
- Participated as a team in faculty's programming competition.
- Dean's list holder for 5 semesters in 2016,2017,2018,2019.
- Earned Vice Chancellor Award in 2019.
- Invited as project's advisor for UPM students in one of faculty's course.

## REFEREE (S)

Amru Yusrin Staff Engineer, Department of Enterprise Government Solutions, Solution Service Delivery, MIMOS Berhad, Technology Park Malaysia, 57000 Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia







+6013-2085373

